Guide to the Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Field Recordings AIA.031.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Private Performances, 1970-1992, circa 1970-Jan 27, 1992
  - Fitzgerald, Bridget (sean nos singer, b. Connemara, Co. Galway) Recording session in Cambridge, MA. Sean nos singer, Fitzgerald was a founding member of Cherish the Ladies. (One CD – Length: 00:10:09) aiamm256, Aug 24, 1985; aiamm256 (Box 2, Folder 19, Box 11)
  - Fitzpatrick, John (accordion) Recording session of the "Drunken Sailor" in Long Island. (Length:00:20:00) aiamm369R, Apr 11, 1978; aiamm369R (Box 36, Box 14)
  - Fitzpatrick, John (accordion), Fitzpatrick, Maureen (fiddle) Eleven tracks separated by yellow leader labeled "Reel One of Two - Mick Moloney Prod." aiamm370R, undated; aiamm370R (Box 24, Box 36)
  - Fitzpatrick, John (accordion), Fitzpatrick, Maureen (fiddle) Recording session in Long Island labeled "Tape 4." (Length: 00:30:00) aiamm366R, Mar 11, 1978; aiamm366R (Box 14, Box 36)
  - Fitzpatrick, John (accordion), Fitzpatrick, Maureen (fiddle) Recording session in Long Island labeled "Tape 6." (Length: 00:30:00) aiamm372R, undated; aiamm372R (Box 36, Box 14)
  - Fitzpatrick, John (accordion), Fitzpatrick, Maureen (fiddle) Tracks separated by yellow leader labeled "Reel Two of Two - Mick Moloney Prod." aiamm371R, undated; aiamm371R (Box 36, Box 24)
  - Fitzpatrick, John (accordion), Fitzpatrick, Maureen (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar) Compilation of mixes labeled "Reel 2." (Length: 00:45:00) aiamm373R, undated; aiamm373R (Box 14, Box 43)
  - Fitzpatrick, John (accordion), Fitzpatrick, Maureen (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar) Compilation of mixes labeled "Reel 3 of 3." (Length: 01:00:00) aiamm374R, undated; aiamm374R (Box 43, Box 14)
  - Fitzpatrick, John (accordion), Fitzpatrick, Maureen (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar) Labeled "1st Half 1st # for Opening." aiamm375R, undated; aiamm375R (Box 17, Box 43)
  - Fitzpatrick, John (accordion), Fitzpatrick, Maureen (fiddle). aiamm647C, undated; aiamm647C (Box 56, Box 27)
  - Fitzpatrick, John (accordion), Fitzpatrick, Maureen (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (bouzouki) Recording session in Long Island labeled "Tape 5." (Length: 00:45:00) aiamm367R, Mar 11, 1978; aiamm367R (Box 36, Box 14)
  - Fitzpatrick, John (accordion), Moloney, Mick (guitar) Recording session labeled "Tape 7." (Length: 00:45:00) aiamm368R, Mar 12, 1978; aiamm368R (Box 43, Box 14)
  - Fitzpatrick, Marjarie A. (vocals) Homemade demo of original unaccompanied song, "Ballad of Ann Marie Murphy." (Length: 00:05:00) aiamm648C, Apr 14, 1993; aiamm648C (Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm648C, Box 43, Cd aiamm648C)
  - Fitzpatrick, Maureen: Interview. aiamm1273C, undated; aiamm1273C (Box 44, Box 65)
  - Fitzpatrick, Maureen: Interview in Massapequa (Long Island), NY. aiamm616R, Feb 26, 1978; aiamm616R (Box 75, Box 67)
  - Fitzpatrick, Maureen (fiddle), Moloney, Mick (guitar, bouzouki), Recording session in Massapequa, Long Island, New York. Fitzpatrick appears on the 1986 Shanachie recording, Fathers and Daughters. (Two CDs – Total length: 00:56:28) aiamm258, 259, Feb 25, 1978; aiamm258, aiamm259 (Box 12, Box 2, Folder 20, Box 11)
  - Fitzpatrick, Maureen (fiddle), Fitzpatrick, John (accordion), Moloney, Mick (guitar) Recording session in Massapequa, Long Island, New York. (One CD – Length: 00:25:30) aiamm260, Feb 26, 1978; aiamm260 (Box 12, Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Fitzpatrick, Maureen (fiddle), Mulvihill, Martin (fiddle) Two short recording sessions. Fitzpatrick plays "Maudabawn Chapel"; Mulvihill plays three of his own compositions. (Length: 00:15:00) aiamm376R, Jun 8, 1977; aiamm376R (Box 56, Box 14)
  - Flanagan Brothers. aiamm1492C, undated; aiamm1492C (Box 72, Box 45)
  - Flanagan Brothers. aiamm1418C, undated; aiamm1418C (Box 44, Box 73)
  - Flanagan Brothers: Re-recorded 78 RPMs (Reel 1). aiamm591R, Jan 1978; aiamm591R (Box 70, Box 45)
  - Flanagan, Mike (banjo, b.1899, Co. Waterford, d. 1990) Private performance and interview in Albany, NY. Flanagan, a pioneering banjo player in the vaudeville era Flanagan Brothers, discusses his personal and musical history followed by songs and instrumentals. (Three CDs – Total length: 01:54:55) aiamm41R, 42R, 43R, Feb 27, 1977; aiamm41R, aiamm42R, aiamm43R (Box 2, Folder 22, Box 8, Box 28)
  - Flanagan, Mike (electric tenor guitar, vocals) Private performance of songs and instrumentals interspersed with very brief interview segments recorded in Albany. (Two CDs – Total length: 01:29:47) aiamm44R, Feb 27, 1977; aiamm44R (Box 28, Box 2, Folder 23, Box 8)
  - Flanagan, Mike (banjo, vocals), Leonard, Mike (banjo, b. Albany, NY, 1935, d. 1997) Private performance of songs and instrumental duets with Leonard, Flanagan's protégé, recorded in Albany. (Three CDs – Total length: 01:10:11) aiamm34R, 35R, Sep 6, 1977; aiamm34R, aiamm35R (Box 8, Box 28, Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Flatley, Michael (flute, b. July 16, 1958, Chicago, IL) Recording session in Chicago. (One CD – Length: 00:05:00) aiamm54R, Mar 5, 1978; aiamm54R (Box 8, Box 2, Folder 25, Box 29)
  - Flying Cloud: Tony DeMarco (fiddle), Brian Brooks (guitar), Dan Milner (vocals) Caesar Pacifici (guitar) Side A: Concert performance. (40 minutes); private performance by Milner of unaccompanied ballads. (20 minutes); Side B: Irish Arts Center session with unidentified musicians including drum kit and highland pipes. (Total length: 02:00:00) aiamm378R, undated; aiamm378R (Box 56, Box 21)
  - Flying Cloud: Tony DeMarco (fiddle), Brian Brooks (guitar), Dan Milner (vocals) Side A: Recording session. (60 minutes); Side B: Brady, Paul (guitar, vocals, whistle) Solo concert performance in the Bronx. (30 minutes) (Total length: 01:30:00). aiamm377R, circa 1977; aiamm377R (Box 21, Box 36)
  - Flynn, Conor: Interview. aiamm1348C, undated; aiamm1348C (Box 71, Box 44)
  - Forde, Declan. aiamm1343C, undated; aiamm1343C (Box 44, Box 71)
  - Four Provinces and Banjo Players. aiamm1294C, undated; aiamm1294C (Box 66, Box 44)
  - Four Provinces Orchestra. aiamm629R, undated; aiamm629R (Box 67, Box 75)
  - Four Provinces Orchestra. aiamm1442C, undated; aiamm1442C (Box 69, Box 44)
  - Four Provinces Orchestra. aiamm1410C, undated; aiamm1410C (Box 44, Box 70)
  - Four Provinces Orchestra. aiamm1376C, undated; aiamm1376C (Box 44, Box 73)
  - Frain, Owen (flute, b. 1896, Co.Mayo) Interview in Boston, MA. Frain, a member of Dan Sullivan's Shamrock Band, discusses his personal and musical history. (One CD – Length: 00:21:10) aiamm4R, Mar 5, 1977; aiamm4R (Box 28, Box 8, Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Frain, Owen and Gene. aiamm1455C, undated; aiamm1455C (Box 66, Box 45)
  - Gershen, Paulette (whistle) Labeled "Northern Reel and Josie McDermott's." aiamm379R, Jul 30, 1985; aiamm379R (Box 56, Box 21)
  - Gershen, Paulette (whistle) Labeled "Rough Mix." aiamm380R, undated; aiamm380R (Box 43, Box 17)
  - Glassie, Henry: Lecture on structuralism. aiamm1244C, undated; aiamm1244C (Box 44, Box 65)
  - Golden, Donny (dancer) Interview. The dance teacher and National Heritage Fellowship recipient discusses his life and dance culture. (Length: 00:45:00) aiamm650C, undated; aiamm650C (Box 25, Box 36)
  - Green Fields of America – Practice (Rehearsal). Musicians include: Mike Rafferty (flute), Jerry O'Sullivan (whistle), Liz Carroll (fiddle), Sean McGlynn (accordion). (One CD – Length: 00:46:10) aiamm166C, 1978; aiamm166C (Box 10, Box 2, Folder 27, Box 34)
  - Green Fields of America – Practice (Rehearsal). Jack Coen (flute), Sean McGlynn (accordion), Mick Moloney (banjo), Fr. Charlie Coen (concertina), Liz Carroll (fiddle) and Bill Ochs (uilleann pipes) practice in San Juan, Puerto Rico. (Two CDs – Total length: 01:06:44) aiamm302R, 303R, May 2, 1979; aiamm302R, aiamm303R (Box 2, Folder 28, Box 33, Box 12)
  - Green Fields of America – Interview. Touring members of the group including Jack Coen (flute), Sean McGlynn (accordion), Mick Moloney (banjo), Fr. Charlie Coen (concertina) and Liz Carroll (fiddle) interviewed in Pittsburgh, PA. Interviewer is unidentified. (One CD – Length: 00:46:37) aiamm127R, May 1979; aiamm127R (Box 9, Box 2, Folder 29, Box 31)
  - Green Fields of America in Milwaukee (Friday I). aiamm1450C, undated; aiamm1450C (Box 44, Box 69)
  - Green Fields of America in Milwaukee. aiamm1453C, 1998; aiamm1453C (Box 72, Box 45)
  - Green Fields of America in Milwaukee (Saturday I and II). aiamm1438C, undated; aiamm1438C (Box 73, Box 44)
  - Green Fields of America in Milwaukee (Sunday II). aiamm1440C, undated; aiamm1440C (Box 73, Box 44)
  - Green Fields of America (group) Rehearal in San Juan, Puerto Rico. Musicians include: Liz Carroll (fiddle), Jack Coen (flute), Fr. Charlie Coen (concertina), Mick Moloney (guitar), Sean McGlynn (accordion), Bill Ochs (uillieann pipes). (Length: 01:30:00) aiamm381R, May 2, 1979; aiamm381R (Box 14, Box 36)
  - Green Fields of America (group) Rehearsal for a show at International House, Philadelphia, PA. Musicians: Jerry O'Sullivan (uilleann pipes), Liz Carroll (fiddle), Mick Moloney (banjo, guitar), Jack Coen (flute), Charlie Coen (concertina), Robbie O'Connell (vocals, guitar). (Length: 00:25:00) aiamm651C, Oct 1, 1984; aiamm651C (Box 25, Box 36)
  - Green Fields of America, Town Hall, New York City (World Music Institute (Tape 1). aiamm2DAT, Dec 4, 1998; aiamm2DAT (Box 76, Box 69)
  - Green Fields of America, Town Hall, New York City (World Music Institute (Tape 2). aiamm4DAT, Dec 4, 1998; aiamm4DAT (Box 68, Box 76)
  - Green Fields of America (group) Labeled "Rehearsal for Record." Musicians include: Jimmy Keane (accordion), Robbie O'Connell (vocals, guitar), Eileen Ivers (fiddle). Moloney narrates arrangements. (Length: 00:45:00) aiamm652C, Jun, 1988; aiamm652C (Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm652C, Box 43, Cd aiamm652C)
  - Green Grass Cloggers. aiamm1430C, undated; aiamm1430C (Box 44, Box 73)
  - Green Grass Cloggers (group) Interview. Members of the North Carolina dance troupe discuss their origins and organization. (Length: 00:25:00) aiamm654C, Dec 4, 1986; aiamm654C (Box 74, Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm654C)
  - Green Grass Cloggers (group) Susie Goff and other old time players play tunes for Moloney in preparation for the Festival of Mountaint Music and Dance. (Length: 00:45:00) aiamm653C, circa 1985; aiamm653C (Box 74, Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm653C)
  - Side A: The Gun Runners; Side B: All Over Ulster. aiamm1403C, undated; aiamm1403C (Box 44, Box 71)
  - Harbison, Janet (harp) Interview. Harbison discusses her life and music. (Length: 00:45:00) aiamm655C, Nov 4, 1992; aiamm655C (Box 74, Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm655C)
  - Harte, Frank (vocals) Labeled "Chapelizod." aiamm656C, Jun 9, 1975; aiamm656C (Box 43, Box 27)
  - Harte, Frank (vocals) Private performance of "King Williamstown" recorded over the phone. (Length: 00:05:00) aiamm657C, undated; aiamm657C (Box 25, Box 36)
  - Harte, Frank. Unlabeled. aiamm1260C, 1973; aiamm1260C (Box 68, Box 44)
  - Hay Down Treaders (group) Demo tape featuring Tim Britton (uilleann pipes, whistle) and Mark Simos (fiddle, guitar, vocals). (Length: 00:15:00) aiamm658C, undated; aiamm658C (Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm658C, Box 43, Cd aiamm658C)
  - Hayes, Martin (fiddle) Audio letter to Jimmy Keane featuring private recordings of twenty-year old Hayes including the latter's compositions (15 minutes) followed by private performances by Jimmy Keane (accordion) (20 minutes). (Total length: 00:35:00) aiamm659C, after 1982; aiamm659C (Box 25, Box 36)
  - Healy, Shay (guitar and vocals, b. 1943) Interview in Nashville, TN. Songwriter and performer Healy discusses composing and performing. (Two CDs – Total length: 01:00:39) aiamm37R, Aug 22, 1974; aiamm37R (Box 8, Box 28, Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Heaney, Joe (vocals, b. 1919, Ardcastle, Carna, Co. Galway, d. 1984) Interview in Bay Ridge, NY. Celebrated sean nos singer Heaney discusses his life and music. (Two CDs – Total length: 01:04:34) aiamm120R, Dec 4, 1981; aiamm120R (Box 31, Box 2, Folder 31, Box 9)
  - Heaney, Joe (vocals) Interview in Bay Ridge, NY. Celebrated sean nos singer Heaney discusses his life and music. (One CD – Length: 00:23:07) aiamm121R, Jan 2, 1982; aiamm121R (Box 2, Folder 32, Box 9, Box 31)
  - Henry, Dermot (guitar, singer, entertainer) Interview on cruise ship. Henry discusses his life, music, showbands and performing in the U.S. (Length: 00:30:00) aiamm660C, Jan 17, 1992; aiamm660C (Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm660C, Box 42, Cd aiamm660C)
  - Henry, Emmet (Barman at Mona's): Interview by Mick Moloney at Ireland House. aiamm11CD, Mar 22, 2004; aiamm11CD (Box 74, Box 76)
  - Henry, Kevin (flute, b. Mar 29, 1929) Recording session in Chicago. (One CD – Length: 00:04:55) aiamm54R, Mar 5, 1978; aiamm54R (Box 2, Folder 33, Box 29, Box 8)
  - Henry, Kevin (flute), Flatley, Michael (flute) Recording session in Chicago. (One CD – Length: 00:10:01) aiamm55R, Mar 5, 1978; aiamm55R (Box 8, Box 29, Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Hughes, Richard (flute) Recording session in Pittsburgh, PA. for the 1979 Rounder release, Light Through the Leaves. (One CD – Length: 00:23:12) aiamm264, Mar 4, 1978; aiamm264 (Box 2, Folder 35, Box 12)
  - Hughes, Richard (flute) Recording session in [Pittsburgh, PA]. for the 1979 Rounder release, Light Through the Leaves. (One CD – Length: 00:06:41) aiamm265R, Dec 11, 1978; aiamm265R (Box 33, Box 12, Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Irish Tradition: Billy McComiskey (accordion), Brendan Mulvihill (fiddle), Andy O'Brien (guitar, vocals) Practice session of tunes and songs in Washington, D.C. (Length: 00:40:00) aiamm661C, Jul 1987; aiamm661C (Box 25, Box 36)
  - Irish Tradition: Billy McComiskey (accordion), Brendan Mulvihill (fiddle), Andy O'Brien (guitar) Labeled "Rough Mix." aiamm382R, undated; aiamm382R (Box 17, Box 78)
  - Irish Tradition: Mulvihill, Brendan (fiddle), McComiskey, Billy (accordion), O'Brien, Andy (guitar, vocals) Recording session in Washington, D.C. (One CD – Length: 00:14:24) aiamm66R, Jul 8, 1977; aiamm66R (Box 2, Folder 37, Box 29, Box 9)
  - Irish Tradition: Mulvihill, Brendan (fiddle), McComiskey, Billy (accordion), O'Brien, Andy (guitar, vocals) Recording session in [?] for the 1991 release, The Music of Ed Reavy. (One CD – Length: 00:14:50) aiamm321R, undated; aiamm321R (Box 12, Box 2, Folder 38, Box 33)
  - Ivers, Eileen (fiddle) Interview about life, music and competing featuring some unaccompanied private performances by thirteen-year old Ivers (10 minutes; Dec 6, 1978); Mulvihill, Gail (banjo, fiddle), Mulvihill, Martin (fiddle) Interview with thirteen-year old Gail and private unaccompanied performance by Martin (10 minutes; Jan 9, 1978); Britton, Tim (uilleann pipes) Ruth, Ben (fiddle) Interview with Britton and private performance (25 minutes); Posen, Shelley (guitar), Moloney, Mick (mandolin) Recording session of "O'Neill's Hornpipe" (5 minutes; Jan 4, 1979). (Total length: 00:50:00) aiamm662C, Dec 6, 1978, Jan 4, 1979, and Jan 9, 1979; aiamm662C (Box 36, Box 25)
  - Ivers, Eileen (fiddle) Studio rough mixes for the album, Hold the Line. (Length: 00:50:00) aiamm663C, 1994; aiamm663C (Box 36, Box 25)
  - Jacobs, Ellen (fiddle) Private performance and interview in Philadelphia, PA. with the Ann Arbor transplant about her involvement with Irish music. (Length: 00:20:00) aiamm664C, Dec 29, 1977; aiamm664C (Box 42, Cd aiamm664C, Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm664C)
  - Johnson, Eric: Guitar Lesson. aiamm1394C, Jul 23, 1975; aiamm1394C (Box 70, Box 44)
  - Keane, James (button accordion and concertina, b. Feb 7, 1948, Dublin) Private performance of traditional music recorded in Queens. (Two CDs – Total length: 00:38:17) aiamm123R, Feb 29, 1976; aiamm123R (Box 31, Box 9, Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Keane, James (accordion). aiamm673C, undated; aiamm673C (Box 78, Box 27)
  - Keane, James (accordion) Interview in New Canaan, CT. upon completion of a recording for Green Linnet. Keane discusses his life and music. (Length: 00:40:00). aiamm665C, Aug 8, 1979; aiamm665C (Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm665C, Box 42, Cd aiamm665C)
  - Keane, James (accordion) Labeled "Interview." aiamm384R, Aug 9, 1979; aiamm384R (Box 78, Box 17)
  - Keane, James (accordion) Labeled "Record Practice." aiamm672C, undated; aiamm672C (Box 27, Box 78)
  - Keane, James (accordion) Performances and interview for the radio program, "Roll Away the Reel World" produced by Leslie Austin. Master copy. (Length: 00:30:00). aiamm385R, 1982; aiamm385R (Box 14, Box 56)
  - Keane, James (accordion) Private performnace of tunes. (Length: 00:30:00). aiamm669C, Oct 7, 1987; aiamm669C (Box 78, Box 25)
  - Keane, James (accordion) Studio recording session with engineer announcing takes. (Length: 00:15:00) aiamm670C, undated; aiamm670C (Box 25, Box 78)
  - Keane, James (accordion) Unaccompanied accordion rough mixes for the 1980 LP Roll Away the Reel World. (Length: 00:30:00). aiamm666C, Aug, 1979; aiamm666C (Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm666C, Box 42, Cd aiamm666C)
  - Keane, James (accordion) Interview by Leslie Austin promoting the album Roll Away the Reel World with music excerpts. (Length: 00:30:00). aiamm668C, 1982; aiamm668C (Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm668C, Box 42, Cd aiamm668C)
  - Keane, James; Carroll, Liz. aiamm1407C, undated; aiamm1407C (Box 44, Box 70)
  - Keane, James (accordion), Keane, Paddy. Labeled "Recorded From James Keane's Tape." aiamm674C, undated; aiamm674C (Box 78, Box 27)
  - Keane, James (accordion), McGlynn, Sean (accordion), Connolly, Mattie (uilleann pipes), Conway, Brian (fiddle) Labeled "Practice, NY." aiamm675C, undated; aiamm675C (Box 56, Box 27)
  - Keane, James (accordion), Moloney, Mick (banjo) Recording session at Keane's apartment in Queens (10 minutes); Fitzpatrick, John (accordion), Fitzpatrick, Maureen (fiddle) Recording session in Long Island. (25 minutes) (Total length:00:35:00). aiamm383R, Jan 22, 1977; aiamm383R (Box 36, Box 14)
  - Keane, James (accordion), Moloney, Mick (guitar) Rough overmodulated studio mixes with count-offs and engineer for the album, Roll Away the Reel World. (Length: 00:20:00) aiamm671C, undated; aiamm671C (Box 78, Box 25)
  - Keane, James (accordion), Moloney, Mick (guitar) and unidentified fiddle. Recording session for Roll Away the Reel World with engineer calling takes. (Length:01:00:00) aiamm667C, circa 1980; aiamm667C (Box 78, Box 25)
  - Keane, James, Sr. (sean nos singer, b. 1928, Carraroe, Co. Galway), Moloney, Mick (banjo), Flatley, Michael (flute), McCullough, Larry (L.E.) (whistle) Private performance of traditional music recorded in Chicago followed by an interview with Keane, Sr. (One CD – Length: 00:21:24) aiamm14R, Mar 24, 1976; aiamm14R (Box 28, Box 8, Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Keane, Jimmy (piano accordion, b. London). Private performance of traditional music recorded in [?]. (One CD – Length: 00:04:28) aiamm283C, Aug, 1985; aiamm283C (Box 12, Box 34, Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Keane, Jimmy (accordion) Labeled "Tunes 86." Keane introduces and performs tunes for Moloney and Robbie O'Connell. (Length: 00:25:00) aiamm677C, 1986; aiamm677C (Box 25, Box 78)
  - Keane, Jimmy (accordion) Labeled "West Coast 93-New Tunes/Order." Compilation tape on which Keane outlines a concert set list for Moloney by alternating private performances and commercial recordings. (Length: 01:00:00) aiamm678C, 1993; aiamm678C (Box 77, Box 25)
  - Keane, Jimmy (accordion) Phone interview about composing tunes (5 minutes); commercial recording of "Barefoot in Gettysburg" played over the phone; all of this is taped over Moloney overdubbing onto rough studio mixes of unidentified record. (Total length: 00:30:00) aiamm676C, Apr 26. 1985; aiamm676C (Box 25, Box 77)
  - Keane, Sean. aiamm645R, Jun 1, 1969; aiamm645R (Box 68, Box 75)
  - Keane, Tommy (uilleann pipes, flute, banjo) Homemade high-quality private performances. (Length: 00:15:00). aiamm679C, Jul 1, 1979; aiamm679C (Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm679C, Box 36)
  - Keegan, Kevin (accordion) Performances in multiple field recording situations. (Length: 01:30:00). aiamm680C, pre 1978; aiamm680C (Box 36, Box 25)
  - Keenan, Paddy (low whistle) Private performance of tunes and airs. Poor sound quality. (Length:00:10:00) aiamm681C, Mar 1, 1980; aiamm681C (Box 25, Box 77)
  - Kelly, Gene (accordion, b. 1909, Conahy, Castlecomer, Co. Kilkenny) Private performance of traditional music recorded in Washington, D.C. (One CD – Length: 00:26:27) aiamm113R, Jul 20, 1976; aiamm113R (Box 30, Box 3, Folder 2, Box 9)
  - Kelly, Gene (accordion) (folder one) Interview in Long Island. Accordionist Kelly discusses his personal history and his musical experiences in New York City, which range from Prohibition to the 1970s. (Three CDs – Total length: 01:45:09) aiamm23R, 24R, Feb 24, 1978; aiamm23R, aiamm24R (Box 8, Box 28, Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Kelly, Gene (accordion) (folder two) Continuation of interview in Long Island, NY followed by a private performance of around thirty minutes of traditional music. (Two CDs – Total length: 01:03:37) aiamm26R, 111R, Feb 24, 1978; aiamm26R, aiamm111R (Box 3, Folder 4, Box 28, Box 9, Box 8, Box 30)
  - Kelly, Gene (accordion), Collins, Gus (flute) Recording session in the Bronx. (Length: 00:40:00). aiamm388R, Oct 2; aiamm388R (Box 36, Box 14)
  - Kelly, Gene (accordion), Mahon, James (piano) aiamm682C, undated; aiamm682C (Box 27, Box 77)
  - Kelly, Gene (accordion), Teahan, Terry "Cuz" (melodeon) Master mixes for the 1977 Topic LP, Old Time Irish Music in America. (Length: 00:30:00) aiamm386R, aiamm386R (Box 14, Box 56)
  - Kelly, Gene (accordion), Teahan, Terry "Cuz" (melodeon) Master mixes for the 1977 Topic LP, Old Time Irish Music in America. (Length: 00:30:00) aiamm387R, aiamm387R (Box 14, Box 56)
  - Kelly, Gene (accordion), Teahan, Terry (accordion) aiamm683C, undated; aiamm683C (Box 27, Box 77)
  - Kelly, James (fiddle), O'Brien, Paddy (accordion), Sproule, Daithi (guitar, vocals) aiamm685C, undated; aiamm685C (Box 27, Box 56)
  - Kelly, James (fiddle), O'Brien, Paddy (accordion), Sproule, Daithi (guitar, vocals) Audio letter from Kelly to Moloney. Kelly introduces private performances by the trio. (Length: 00:30:00). aiamm684C, late 1970s; aiamm684C (Box 36, Box 25)
  - Kelly, Jimmy. aiamm687C, undated; aiamm687C (Box 56, Box 27)
  - Kelly, Jimmy (vocals, guitar) and "Donna and Pat." Labeled "Irish American Songs, Practice Tape For Nash. Concert." Two vaudeville medleys with close harmony, guitar and Rhodes. (Length:00:10:00) aiamm686C, undated; aiamm686C (Box 77, Box 25)
  - Kelly, Micky (vocals, stories) Private performances from Draperstown, Derry singer storyteller recorded and introduced by Bill Ochs as a demo. (Length:00:30:00) aiamm688C, 1978; aiamm688C (Box 25, Box 77)
  - Kennedy, Seamus (vocals, guitar, b. 1949, Belfast, Co. Antrim) Interview. Kennedy discusses his personal and musical history with specific reference to the Irish bar scene in America. (One CD – Length: 00:43:46) aiamm234C, Sep 22, 1991; aiamm234C (Box 34, Box 11, Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Kilfenora Ceili Band: Interview. aiamm1369C, undated; aiamm1369C (Box 71, Box 44)
  - Killen, Lou. aiamm1466C, undated; aiamm1466C (Box 45, Box 69)
  - Knock na Shee (group) Demo featuring Jo Allen, Marty Somberg and Mark Simos. (Length: 00:30:00) aiamm389R, undated; aiamm389R (Box 14, Box 56)
  - Lavin: Frankie (Copy of tapes). aiamm604R, undated; aiamm604R (Box 69, Box 45)
  - Leonard, Mike (banjo, b. Albany, NY, 1935, d. 1997), Moloney, Mick (guitar, banjo) Private performance and interview recorded in Albany, NY. Leonard, a student of Mike Flanagan of the Flanagan Brothers, discusses his musical history and Irish music in the Albany area, followed by around twenty-six minutes of traditional music. (Two CDs – Total length: 00:42:12) aiamm42R, 43R, Feb, 1977; aiamm42R, aiamm43R (Box 28, Box 8, Box 3, Folder 6)